Now that Gerry is here telling us on Jerry Jones, we hit the record button.
So I wanted to do. Yeah, I just wanted to share something totally unrelated to code, right?
But you know, you're all sitting on on on Zoom, right?
And I'm sitting here and you see, you know, me coding, talking, whatever it may be, but I wanted to share with you how blown up my screen is.
Can you see that? Yeah, so that's that's me teaching to you.
But right when you when you see it from your end, kind of here, let's get rid of it.
Come on this. That's what you see. All right.
So I just thought I'd share that because Zoom, right, does a really good job of allowing me to zoom in my screen, right?
And allow you to see, like I said, just the normal view.
So, yeah, and that's that's why you never want to allow me to drive a car, right?
Because I I'm like, I don't know. There used to be a kids cartoon called Mister Mr Magoo.
I don't know that it remembers that, but he he was a character that drove around and he couldn't see.
So thankfully, my wife read it. Yeah, I remember this and go, Yeah.
So yeah, thankfully, my wife and, you know, friends, you know, drive, drive me around.
All right. So let's get started. Let's get started. We're in.
We're nearing the end. This is the last module. This is like the last like full module on on something called classes, the finding classes,
which you've already done using the graphics library, but you didn't know much about it other than, Hey, here's I want to.
I want a graphics window. I want to circle. I want all all these things.
But how can we like develop those types of things on our on our own right?
So that's what this module is all about. This is the last problem set.
This is the last learning guide. Clear. This is the last written quiz.
And next Monday. I don't think we'll have class because it's Thanksgiving week.
There won't be any need on. Some of you wanted to take the Microsoft Python certification.
So there is a schedule and canvas under the Microsoft MTA section, and there's a couple of things in there that's wanted to share with you.
OK? Number one is you need to schedule your exam time with me, either from Monday, December six or Friday, December 10th.
And some of you have done that already, and I appreciate that. I recommend that you take the exam on Monday this way if you don't pass it.
And I've failed quite a few of these in my time, a fewer.
So you'll be able to retake it on Friday if you don't pass it.
All right. Just say it. So we give you two opportunities to take it.
So here is the information right here. You all should have access to it.
I want you to schedule your your exam with me and bye bye.
If you have an inkling to take any of these other Microsoft certification exams,
there is one on C-sharp and I know we have a c sharp programmer in the class here.
So just note that not only can you take Python, but you can schedule all these others to and I'd be happy to provide them to you.
Practice them for you in person a class on either Monday, December six or Friday, December 10.
No cost to you. Just just know that these are free.
There is no cost to you. So what you need to do is you need to like, like email me and say, Hey Bruce,
I want to schedule h html on Monday night and I want to schedule a python at one o'clock, you know, just just like that.
All right, here's the instructions. It's all right here, right?
And the next thing you want to do is I've some of you may have used this before, but we have access to practice tests.
It's called G Metrics. They're the name of the company that makes it.
So if you go through all these steps here, right,
and you enter this magical code right here and select the Microsoft and then Python or whatever exam you want to study for,
you'll be able to get to practice exams so you can do these practice exams and in practice mode where you get to see the answer after each question.
Or you can go in a full on simulation mode where it's timed right and and stuff like that, right?
So again, I provide you with the resources. Usually everyone who takes us passes it.
Is it 100 percent of the material that I taught? You know, is it 90 percent?
Yeah. Is the other 10 percent of the knowledge that you would need to know in some of these key metrics practice exams?
Heck, yeah. All right. So that's why everyone usually passed it.
And just so, you know, write these things, and I think you all know the story, right?
If you go into. Go back to like the beginning of time here with module zero.
I think I had like information about me and I've taken.
All these various Microsoft certifications over time since I started it, Clark, I mean, I should know all this stuff because I teach a lot of it,
but the ones that I did fail are ones that I don't have much experience with, which is like the Java programing language.
That's the one I that kicked my butt a lot. So I had to learn Java, you know, over two months, and I finally, I finally passed it.
And when you have these things, they also go on your LinkedIn and you know, and you can put them on your portfolio or wherever it may be.
And I've said this before, every day I'll get a job request through LinkedIn for especially Python because it's such an in-demand language right now.
And the other thing too, is LinkedIn has a little certification exam that you can take to prove your skills.
And it was hard. Yeah, I wouldn't go take it right away because you can only take it twice within a six months time and after that, you have to wait.
All right. So that's it on certifications, you know, are they required?
No. Are they helpful? Yes. Are they good to have?
Yeah. All right. Any questions before we get started?
Any, any thing, anyone have any questions that I can answer.
Nothing in the chat. All right. And for those of you who did send me the code words for the announcement that
came out yesterday about watching that video or those videos before class?
Thanks. Thanks for doing that. I think I got for people who replied back, So cool.
And let's get started. If there's no questions, so let's get started and you can all see my screen right?
Just checking, right? Yeah, you can see it. All right. Thanks, Brandon.
So let's start off. Let's start off. Let me just call it the demo.
Demo Dash one dot pi. OK, just like that. And let's.
Pretend, well, let's pretend this is kind of those of you who watch the video, this is kind of what we're going to do.
Let's pretend I keep saying it. Let's create some code where we can model a physical dye, a dye that you use for playing board games,
whether it's a six sided dye or a hundreds thousands sided dye or a, you know, a 20 sided dye.
I don't know what the gamers. I know my son.
My son has this big dye with all. I don't know what game it is. Maybe you can tell me,
but let's say we wanted to create a template where we could create a dye and then maybe we can create 10000 dye and we could roll them.
We could do anything we wanted to do with the dye.
Typically, it's you roll the dye, and that's kind of about it, right?
So how would we go about creating a piece of software?
Something called a class, a class or a template to model a multi-sided DI.
OK, so let's do it. We're going to learn a new keyword in Python.
And the key word is class. Class Class C L a ss all lowercase.
And now you're going. Do you remember with the graphics library when you had like circle, it was uppercase, right?
When you had graph, when it was uppercase, right when you had rectangle or polygon?
Right. They all started with a capital letter. And that's when you define a class A template you or a blueprint.
Right? You use a capital letter. So let's create a a class name called DI.
No parentheses. None of that. And just a colon.
Just like that. OK. Just like that.
So we're going to create a template, a cookie cutter that we're going to use to to fabricate die.
This right in software in Python. OK, so here we go.
I hit enter and it's like, it's like, All right.
What goes inside of here, what goes inside of our class?
Well, a whole bunch of things, right? A whole bunch of things.
But when you created a graphics window, when you created a circle and you created a rectangle, a polygon.
Any of these things? As soon as you created them?
Right. Those are what we call.
We instantiated them, right? We we we fabricated that right.
So with a dye right with a dye?
Does anyone want to tell me when we say, go to make a dye, make believe we have a factory in Vancouver here and we may die, right?
So what are some properties of a dye?
Anyone want to just belt some out to me?
What are some things that when I look at it, dye, right?
What can you describe some of its properties, right? I have brown hair looks gray, right?
I'm five foot nine hundred ninety five pounds.
Those are some properties right about Bruce, right? So what are some properties of a dye?
Anybody. How many sides? It has number of sides, Common says.
I'll I'll take that. So let me just do this.
Uh, properties properties. OK, so the first thing is, no, actually, I'm not going to use my triple two three doing.
Oops. Number of side. I have a plug in that extension that I need to turn off.
Please hold. Please hold. I just turn this on doc.
Pi. Can anyone see Python? Doc stream, yeah, I want to turn this off, although I could disable.
Sorry about that reload. OK, so here we go.
Number of signs. Properties, OK, what else, what else?
Collins, right? Number of sites.
Let's say you go to Fred Meyer and you buy or you go to the bat cave and you buy some dye and they're in a package, right?
What do you see? What do you see when you look at that, that set of dye?
What do you see anybody the same shape? OK, well, we'll leave that for now.
OK, shape, Jojo says. What else? OK, what about the bears?
Usually? OK, so they're packaged in pairs.
But tell me about one day, Joshua. Tell me about one guy. Tell me about one guy when you look at it, right?
If you know, how about six sizes depending on the deal you're looking at?
Yes, that's right. So that's what Colin said. Number of sides.
Let's say you look at the shelf and you see a package of dye, right?
When you look at that package of dye, right, you'll notice that they have a certain number of sides.
But what else do you see? What else do you see? No, that numbers right.
So but those numbers, Gerri correspond to the site or when you look, does each dye, especially when, like when you roll a dye,
how many values kind of dye have like during a game, like when you roll the dice,
do you look at the side of the dye or do you look at the side facing up?
Side face it, when you the side facing off and facing up is labeled a no.
So what would you call that? What would you call that that that?
Would it be the the the value? What do you call like when I rolled of five, right?
If I roll of five, what do you call that? Five? Can we call it value is a technical term for it?
We could call it a value because that's that's what you get. All right.
So we'll call it a value. I'm going to just not use the shape pronounce just because I'll take it a little while.
But is it fair to say that the dye that we need to fabricate has a certain number of sides and it's going to have a value, right?
Whether it's what the value is in the package, when Jerry is looking at it on the shelf,
or it's when Ben is using it to play a game with with his friends, right?
We could also add in here color. Right? The dye has a certain color, right?
Maybe. I don't know. I don't think that's necessary right now. Let's just stick with we make dye that have a certain number of sides.
And when we either package them in, you know,
a box or whatever that there is either a value showing on the dye or when Ben uses them in his game, they they have a value.
So those two things are the same.
So how do we create in the software a dye that has, I don't know, six sides will go with four now and has a default value.
Let's just say we have that single dot when we package our dye in our factory in Vancouver,
all the dye are placed in the packaging the same way, with the number one showing by default.
OK. Let's just go with with that for now. So again, how do we construct this dye in software?
Well, there is something we need to do.
And you remember from last week when we created these functions,
we are going to create a special type of function called a constructor constructor function,
which gets run ran when we create a new dye in our software.
OK. So what we do is we create a special name called Double actually what this is called.
Let me just do this right here. And then just like that.
Now this is weird, OK? This is really weird. It's a reserve word in Python, and it it's two underscores the word init,
which stands for initialize and then two more underscores and then a set of parentheses I'll call in.
OK. And we usually say for these double underscore, as we'll say, Dunder Dundar, not Dunder Mifflin Dunder double underscore.
And what this says is when you create, when you construct, when you initialize a new dye, we need to do the following.
OK, so check it out. We put this word in here called self.
And remember, we're dealing with objects. They have the ability to to know things about them, and they can also do things.
So our dye, when we create it, it's going to say, Hey, self.
OK, what's your value? What what's your value and what's your number of sites?
So now we're going to say, Hey, self. What's your value and let's set all of our die to have a default value of one?
OK. Now again, I know some of this is highly, you know, just way out in left field right now, but just stick with me.
So by default, when we create a new die or a new object or a new template, right, which we're doing here or by a class may just fix us up here.
We say we create the class name, right?
I called it die uppercase.
We create our constructor function, constructor function and this get run as soon as we create a new die, which we haven't done yet.
We're just creating the template for what happens when we create a new die, just like we did with a new graph when a new circle, a new rectangle.
It had a constructor which said, Hey, when when you let me carry on.
So when we create the die, we're setting itself to have a value one and we're setting the number of sides to six.
We're going to stick with a six sided die. OK, so believe it or not, believe it or not,
what we've done here is we have created a template to make six sided die that have a default value of one.
OK, now. Just take that in for a second.
Okay, take that in, and it'll make a lot more sense as soon as I construct my first day.
Can I check it? Here we go.
Here we go. Let's just call it die one variable name.
Die one. Just like you did with Circle, you created Circle one, Circle two or i1 I two, right?
I just call them create a variable called die one. And I said, Hey, die one.
I want you to create a new die. Just like that. Just create a new die, just like we did with graph one and other things.
There is no parameters yet for our die.
We're just if you create a die, just like I did here, we're saying, Hey, hey, hey, class,
create a new die that has a default value of one and six sides and store it in this variable called die one by one.
Now everyone's like, All right, if I print out the type of die one, do you think it's going to be a a string?
Be an integer or c an object on a integer B string C object?
What do you think? Line 13 is going to print out.
Take a there's no wrong guesses here. Somebody take a guess. Object, I mean, string, an integer string or object.
I think in strength. So, Jojo, to your point.
We have won a default value of one.
That's that's that little snake eyes staring at us in on the dye and the dye has six sides.
So could we represent both these bits of information as a string?
Or is it like when we created a circle, the circle had a center point and the circle had a radius,
so which was an object, so integer string or object?
You're going to stick with your answer, Joshua, what do you want to change it? You want to buy a vowel?
Everybody I didn't think about. All right.
So when we created a circle was a circle, an integer, a string or an object.
And I just want to know it's an object, right? It's an object, so we're doing the same thing.
We've created our own object that we made right here, right?
And if I print out, it's tight. It says, in fact, that it is made.
Of a die, so this believe it or not, this is telling you that this variable die one is an object and in fact it is.
It is a die. It is a die, which is which is an object.
It's not a string. It's not an integer, right?
It's an object. Because Jojo, check it out.
I can then say print die one dot, just like we did with the graphics library.
And look what we get here size and value. So let's just do sides.
And now we're going to print out right sides. Sides is a prop.
Remember when we did like? I'm trying to remember an example where we just used a property like this, but let me just run it so you can see it.
And now it's telling me that that dye that we created has six signs that Dye one has six sides and that dye one has a value its current value looks.
I can't type today. Its value is going to be.
One. Okay, now we've created a model of a die in software, now we've created one die with it for our program to use.
But if we want to create a second, die a second, die here, I'm just going to copy this code, copy this code.
Put it here and change die one to die to.
Right, I mean, just put a print here. Die, too.
And I'll print. A. A print die one.
So you can see that we've created. Today.
Although one second, I think they did it. Here it is.
So we've created die one right here. Let me show me sorry, this is a little theaters die one.
It's made of a die. It has six sides. The current value is one in the package.
Then we have a die to, which is made for a die, has six sides and has a face value of one.
So using not really take one. So using this one set of code right here, using this one set of code, I've created two dice.
Two dice, right? Two dice. Two dice.
I can go on and on and I can create other die using this, but that's not going to be any fun.
And when we do things like this, we're having to create variables for each one of those die, which is probably not a good thing.
You learned a few weeks ago about list and how a list can be like a bag of dye.
It can have multiple dice inside of it. All right.
So let's just put this aside for now and let me create another demo that's going to expand on this die a little bit.
So I'm going to do control and I'm going to paste in the code.
I'm going to save it. I'm going to call it Demo Dash to.
Don't. I think. Demo Test two PI.
And there's my die. There it is. There is my template to make die.
Now this is all well and good. If we just want to be able to create like one die or, you know, a million die.
Okay. So what we want to be able to do is to be able to give our guy something that a real die would have.
And when you're playing a game, what's the one thing you do with a die?
What do you do with it, you? Roll it, you roll it right.
So how do we give our die that we're creating?
Thanks, Robert. By the way, how do we create a method or a way that our die can do something?
And in this case, it's how could we make it so we can roll it via software and by rolling it?
What is the one property of that die that's going to change?
It's not going to change and morph into having more or less sides.
But what's going to be the one thing that changes when after we roll a die anybody?
What's going to be under my eyes? Yeah, but what what?
That but what what property of that guy gets randomized? What what property on line three or four of my code gets randomized?
Which property there? Besides the assures, so when I roll the die, the number of side change or does the value change Jojo?
But I guess like the side that you're meeting. So yeah, the the value, right?
That's the the the number of facing up, right?
So we're playing. Yeah, yeah, I gotcha.
So what we want to do is we want to define a new method called roll.
Let's just call it roll, roll roll. And then we're going to say, Hey, self, hey di you, I'm talking to you.
Roll yourself, right? And then I'm going to say, like Jojo said, we need to be able to now generate a random number, right?
Because Ben is playing this game and he's writing a software game and he rolls that AI, right?
So he's going to say, Hey, software guy that we haven't created in this demo yet.
I need you to generate a random number between one and six, because that's the number of sites that you have.
So here I go. Ready. I'm going to say, Hey, self.
I need you to set your value to. Some random number between one and six.
So anyone does anyone realize what functionality we need to bring into our code at this point to help us generate a random number, I hear somebody.
We need to import random. Yes, Ben.
So Ben is like, Hey, Bruce from the random library from random import rand.
Right?
Because Rand gives us and we've used this over and over again and write a set of random integers, random whole numbers inclusively between two things.
So could we not write do this?
Could we say Hey rand and generate a number, generate a number from one to one comma one to the number of sides that this particular guy has?
I didn't order code six because I'm saying, Hey di, look at yourself.
How many sides do you have? How many sides you have?
Look at yourself and the diocese. Oh, I got six.
So what it's going to do now is going to generate a random number between one and six and tell itself that that is its new value.
Just just like that. OK. Just like that. So what I can do in my code now, I'm out, didn't it all the way?
I have my di template and my dye template has two properties, right?
These are properties. Let me label these properties right.
And this down here is a method, right? Remember the when we took an object in the graphics library and we told it to draw itself, draw is a method.
Notice the method. Start with lowercase letters, right?
The class name starts with a capital letter, and we're not returning anything.
We're just saying, Hey, look at yourself, change the value of yourself from one to the number of sides that you have.
So let's go create our die one again. We're going to say die one equals create a new die, just create a new day.
And then we're going to say, Hey, die one actually print out, Hey, die one.
Print out the number of sides. Print out your value.
Print out your value. Tell me what your value is. And by default, that value is one because we haven't told our die to roll itself in code yet.
We just fabricated instantiated a new die.
So here it is, right down here. It's one we have one as the default value showing in our die when we created it.
So now if I say, Hey, die one. Hey, day one, I want you to take yourself and role yourself role as a method role is something that a guy can do.
It's not a prop., it's something that a guy can do.
And now if I just copy this line of code again, if I copy this line of code again,
hey, day one, what is your value after we asked you to roll yourself ready?
Let me run it. Do I did I point out there it is.
So one in one? Let me run it again. One in six.
One in five. One in four. One in six. One in five. One in two.
One and one one. And two one in five one in three six.
So do you see how we were able to create in the software?
A cookie cutter template to create a day when we created it, right?
This is a code that gets run when we do this line.
12. It gives itself a default value of one and six sides, and then we're asking our dye that we created to roll itself.
And we're setting its value that it knows it is, this is what we call an instance variable.
It kind of in this instance where we created Die One, it knows what value it's set to and that is one in fixed.
OK, but when we roll it, we're changing that value to be some number between one and the number of sides.
That particular dye has. What are you thinking about classes so far?
What what kind of questions are coming to mind kind of abstract?
Is this a very abstract concept? A little bit.
And then like. Well, I. Just because you're putting everything into one like what we were doing before, but now it's all into one group.
A group. So what Robert's referring to is, Bruce, you have these functions here.
Right? One of them has this weird name called Thunder and Thunder, and this other one is a regular one that you kind of recognize.
But they're all grouped together under this.
Class that is known as die. Right?
So, Robert? Yes, to that point.
A class is defined of a bunch of functions because again, going back to the graphics library when you created a new rectangle,
you could set it fill, you could set its outline, you could clone it.
There's a whole bunch of things that a rectangle was able to do,
and what we're doing is we're just mimicking that whole concept we learned with objects and the graphics library.
By creating our own objects that have properties right and are able to do what we need a thing to do and will do way more of these other than to die.
But Robert, does that help a little bit clarifying what's going on?
Yeah, it makes sense. But then like around like what?
I guess Line 11, would you normally put that in the main two? Yeah.
So Ben was Ben was on my shoulder and he's like, Bruce, you should really put that code in the main here.
Let me just do that. Is that better?
And that makes sense now. Yeah. I'm sorry.
Yeah. Yeah. I'm sorry about that. So and on that we were to change the value and the sides.
Would we have to create a new class? No.
So all right. So right now, our class is pretty boring, right?
It only creates six sided die with a default value of one.
Right? Now what if Ben's like, I want a 20 sided die?
OK, ready. Let me run the code. Let me run the code, and the default value is one, and when we roll it, it gets 14.
Two, 10, 14, C, so by just changing the template.
Let's say we want the default value now to be. 20.
Right when you when we manufacture or die and we box them up and we put them all together,
the default face that showing is the number 20 right or twenty two.
I don't know what the multi-sided dial look like, but now see how the default value of our dye is always 20.
And it's randomly generating a number between one and 20 when we roll the dye.
OK, Joshua are thinking about like, if we create more dye, well, we're going to get what I want by two.
Yeah, we're going to create. We're going to create a bag of dye, right?
So not that this has this is not a bag of dye, it's a bag of coins, right?
So I know you have like these bags where you put your dye in, right?
So how could we like write software that creates this bag of dye and a whole bunch of dye inside of it?
Right? And that's what I'm going to show you next. Before we before we carry on.
All right. So again, let me just go back to one here.
And even if we just make this a one sided dye, you can see here.
Let the default value is always one, right? The default value is always one.
And then when we roll it, it gets a new value between one and the number of sides that are available to that die.
And if I do this just so you can see loss here, I'll say.
Original. Value. And then I'll put here.
After rolled. Now when I run it.
One and then five. One an ABC.
OK, now let me just let me there's a couple more things we need to do here.
This is great. We've created one die. How boring, right?
So the question becomes right, how can we create is anyone?
Can gamers who use die? How many does a game typically have one die?
Or sometimes you have multiple die? That sometimes has multiple die.
All right. So how many die would you have? Well, and one of the games they have, like one of the main guys that we have is like spies.
OK, so let's go with say, Lindsay has been hired by a local company to write a pilot program,
and she needs to be able to simulate a game that has a bag that contains five dye.
And how many sides do those dye have? I'm just curious.
Is excited, 20 excited. Well, like for each star, I would be like six to seven on that side.
OK, let's just go with this that we need to create five die.
And we need to be able to, like, take those die in my hand,
shake my hand and then roll the die out on to the table and I can then read all of their their values.
Okay, so check this out. Actually, I'm going to go on the Demo three.
I'm just going to take all this code and copy it into Demo three, just so I don't mess too much stuff up.
Let me go. Demo three here. Demo three Dog Pie.
Paste in that code, right? And now I'm going to operate a little bit.
Okay. So I'm not I'm just going to cut this out for now, and let's create a variable called bag of.
Dice a bag of dice, bag of dice.
And if you remember in coding, when we want to put multiple things into a single variable, we create an empty list,
an empty list and you saw me do this when we learned about lists, how I could take,
you know, a bunch of circles and put the circles into a list and then draw those circles.
So here is my my empty bag of dye.
There's nothing in here right now. All right. So how can we programmatically in software create a new dye?
And add it and place it into our bag of dice.
OK, so let's do it. How do we do something five times what the programing concept?
You're sick and tired of hearing me say, What do we do when we need to do something five times?
Loop it. Yeah, loop it counted loop for Iron Range of five.
We want to put five dye into our bag, so what we can now do is we can say, Hey, bag of dice, I want you to append to you.
A new die just like that. That's weird. So online, 15, I'm saying, hey, bag of dice,
I want you to append because that's how we glue and place new things into our bag of tie into our list and then instead of a string and integer,
I'm just saying, Hey, create a new dye just like that. Just die open, close parentheses, just like that.
And now, if I print out just at the end here, if I say print out what is the length of our bag of dice,
which is going to tell us how many things are in that list, if I run this now, I should have five.
Die in that back. Okay, there they are. I can't I'm only pointing out the length right now.
I haven't even rolled the dice or done anything yet.
But I want to just break this down for you just a little bit easier because I think when we create a new die and we place it into this bad egg,
I'm thinking That's. Well, let me let me let me see if I can explain.
So what I'm going to do here is it's going to say lowercase dye equals dye just like that.
OK. There it is. There it is. I created a variable called dye lowercase.
Die, and I said, create a new die and hold on to it as a bat, as a variable called die,
and then what I'm going to do is I'm going to say, Hey, die, roll yourself before we stick you in the back, hey, die, roll yourself.
And then we're just going to add into the bag. That roll die.
OK. So instead of having a bag of dye that just has all the values the same because when I stick a guy in here,
it's going to it's going to roll around, right? It's just it's not going to be one.
So before we stick that guy into the back, we're going to roll it.
We could roll it a thousand times if we wanted to using a loop.
But here's what I'm going to create a dye from the dye class.
Roll the dye. Append the dye into the list just like that.
OK, so here's what I printed out the length print out the number of dye objects in the bag just like that.
But now how do I see the value?
Of each guy, how do I see the value of each day?
This variable contains a list of the five die.
So being what we've learned in this class, could I say for every I'll just call it for every.
Yeah, we'll call it die in the bag of dice for every.
Every guy that's in that bag of dice, could I say print out died dot value?
Can I say, Hey, hey, Don, what's your current value? And if I run this right and I'll go back and comment and the second if I run this.
You can see here now we have five, five five four one five.
If I create another bag of dye. Five, six, three, six, four, five five.
We're getting all these different value of as we're manufacturing, you know, bags of dice on our assembly line.
They're they're coming out with all these five dye because that's how many Lindsey said we needed in each bag.
But if we dumped out the dove from each one?
There they are there the the dye coming out differently each time.
And if we needed to create a set of dye that has like a bag of dye or a package that contains 100 dyes, we just change our loop to 100.
And now we get 100 dye of all different rolled values, a bag of dyes or packaged dyes whenever we want to call it.
Just like just like that. So let me let me break this down to iterate.
Loop right through each item and list.
Print out objects, value property.
So here is our completed beginner way to create.
A dye that contains six sides by default, the value of that dye is one.
We created a list, an empty list. Create empty list.
Loop one 100 times. And there you go.
We create a new dye. We roll that dye.
We then print out the length and then we iterate through the bag of dice one guy at a time and we print out its value.
How many different variable names did we create?
For the die. None. I mean, one, we only have this bag of dice.
So remember that the purpose of the list is to hold multiple things.
In this case, the things are not integers, they're not strings, but they're die.
And the two things that each guy has is a face value.
And a set number of sides. So this is kind of neat until right until.
Nathan, our boss says, you know, this is all well and good, we're able to create new dye, but I don't always want six sided die.
I may want a 20 sided die or a four sided die or a million sided right.
Okay, so we're going to be looking how to handle these types of things, because right now everything is hardcoded right here.
It's hard coded. We're saying when you instantiate a new dye, when you create a new dye one, and it's exciting any and all times.
Okay? You hear me say this each class, we don't write a lot of code, right?
But it's these concepts. And if you're going into web development, when we start talking to databases,
you know we're going to use this same type of concept where we connect to a database and then we're going to get a whole bunch of maybe.
You know, social media post back and then we're going to, you know, be able to do things with those social media posts, right?
Get the count, the count of likes that the number of comments, right?
So a post right is an object.
Then it contains information about the number of likes, the number of comments, right?
Whether it has images and we can it, we can do things with that particular, you know, social media post.
But that's what we'll save that for another day. So let's move on now and just step in through here and we're going to copy all this code again.
Copy all this code again. But we are now going to create a code.
That's going to not have a hard coded.
Face value or a hard coded number of sides?
Okay, so how do we do this?
How do we let me just check the time here? 10:53. How do we how do we how do we do this?
So what we do is when we create or instantiate a new dye.
We're going to add some parameters after herself, we're going to say, Hey,
I want you to have a default value of something and I want you to have a certain number of sides because when we create this new dye,
we are going to specify what we want the face value to be and the number of sites.
So what we're going to do here now is we're going to change this from a one to that variable that we're passing in called value.
And we're going to change this to the number of sides you want me to manufacture or instantiate or create that dye with.
So now you see that when we construct a new dye, it's got this self parameter here that always has to be there.
We're not going to do anything, but it's just a thing of the language that says this parameter needs to say,
Hey, self, look at yourself in the mirror. All right, cool. I know who I am.
And then it's going to get a value. And the number of sites?
OK. But when we're creating our die right here on Line 15, we now need to say how many what you want,
the default value to be and all that make it one here.
And how many sides do you want? The die to be will make it 100.
OK. So does anyone see the problem?
It's not a problem where this when we create this new dye work, we're saying that it requires three things stealth value inside.
But you start me. Just add to right here the value and the number of sites.
Now I want you to know that this is implied where we don't we don't specify self here on Line 15.
You don't do that won't work if it's just a weird thing in the language that's going to screw with your mind.
So when I run this now, I'm going to create a dye that's going to have a default value of one and 100 sides.
So check this out. Here we go. We actually I want to cut this number down just so you know, from one hundred to five.
Let's go back to five. I'm going to create a bag of five dye that are going to be default value of one and have 100 sides.
So here I go. There they are five, seventy five, eighty four, eighty two,
eight and seventy six and now when when Nathan says no, we need to make a run now of 100000 sided die.
Cool. There they are. They are there different die coming out?
Why are there six numbers? One is the length that's coming out, right, right here.
Oh, OK. Yeah. So let me get rid of that. So you can see.
So now I'm creating a bag of five dye that are 100000 sides.
And I did not hard code into my into my class anything any hard, hard numbers like one or four or five when I create this dye right here.
I'm passing in. The default value I want it to be and the number of sides I want that die to be.
OK. We're at the end of the quarter, you have to imagine that the content gets a little bit more tricky, right?
And this is, you know, it's not easy stuff to comprehend.
So I think we'll do some, some some more examples instead of die.
Maybe we'll do stuff with cars or animals or players or just about anything, any physical object that exists we can represent as a class.
Okay. Thank.
So again. We didn't create separate Barrack that values for the five type of variables for each die.
We just had one variable, which happened to be a list and a list can contain multiple things inside,
and each one of those things happened to be a dye object.
That dye object had a value and it knows how many sides it has, and each dye can do something.
By being able to roll itself, by being able to roll it and again when we do the animal classes in a second,
you'll start to see this take shape a little bit a little bit more.
Okay. When I first learned object oriented programing, which you're learning here it was, it was really hard.
It wasn't until I really started teaching it that it started making more sense.
Takes a while, takes a lot to wrap your head around. OK, let's do.
Let's do some more. Let's start from the very beginning. There we go.
Should we do cars or animals? Anybody cars or animals or something else?
Anyone have any? What about involves animals?
All right. We'll do animals. All right. So what does crate demo Dash five Pi?
Animals. OK, here we go. Just like animals, we sing that song.
I don't know. Just another five. Yeah, Maroon five.
Thank you, Colin. All right. So let's create. Let's do dogs.
Let's do dogs. Let's create a dog class. We're going to manufacture.
Digital dogs, digital dogs.
OK, so there is a good name for our class, remember that the first letter of our class name gets capitalized circle rectangle, polygon, right?
All graph, win all capital. Those are classes. And now let's create our constructor function when we create a new dog.
Right? Define Dunder init. Dunder.
Self. Okay, so by default, when we construct a new dog, we're just going to do that, but.
What are some properties that we should have for our dogs?
I hear list of actually not all software list, but.
Property properties, list of properties of dogs.
So tell me what are some things? If we're like manufacturing dogs, right?
What are some things, what are some properties dogs have? What are some properties?
Dogs have somebody. OK, breed, keep going.
Gender. Gender and what else keep going.
Color, color, size. OK, good, small, medium, large, yeah.
Keep going. What else?
It's not a trick question, just saying go look name.
All right, cool. What about wait, wait.
How about legs? Kyle.
What else? Watch your ears.
Yeah, they all have different irritants, but let's let's just for now focus on breed, gender, color, size, name.
We'll get rid of all this stuff. We'll just focus on these five properties from now.
All right. List. Of methods.
That dogs can do so. Tell me some things dogs can do.
What are some things? That dogs can do. They can bark, they can bark.
They can run, they can run, they can jump, they can eat, they can jump.
Then they can go potty right there. Fair list of things that our dogs and our.
Code that we're going to right here can do. Yeah.
Yes, Chris. All right. So what we want to do now is we want to when we construct a new dog, right?
We want to be able to give it a breed. A gender.
A color a size. Name.
OK. So when we create a new dog in our software code.
We're going to want to give it a brief gender, color, size and a name.
Can you? Makes sense so far when we create a new doc, so self.
Hey, dog, I want your breed to be whatever value we gave you to construct yourself.
Hey, well, hey, I want your color to be whatever color we told you to be.
And then I moved the Zoom window here. I want your.
Sized to be whatever size I told you to be. And I want your name to be whatever name I told you to be.
OK, so let's cut it off first dog, OK?
I think his name a reserved word in Python. Maybe so give me.
Let me credit me in here. Ben to mean.
Does anyone have a dog that anyone have a dog?
I have a dog. His name is lucky and he's kind of our team right now.
All right. So I created a book called Lucky. There it is.
Lucky the dog and we're going to make lucky a dog.
And now we need to give our software the breed.
So the breed is going to be a string, right? The breed is going to be a string.
So. Lindsay, what kind of dog is lucky?
Lucky is a black lab slash border collie, black lab slash border.
Colony. OK, now the next thing is gender.
What's the gender of the dog, male male and what is the color of your dog lacked?
OK. What is the size? Is it a large dog? It's a medium.
All right. Medium. And what is? Oh, it's lucky.
There it is. Right? All right. So now just by doing this code right here, I've created Lindsay's dog in software, right?
There it is. I have created Lindsay's dog in software.
In fact, if I say print out what kind of dog is lucky, I'll say breed just like that, it's going to come back and tell me that Lindsay's dog.
Is an error, OK, has no attribute name. I knew a new name was going to give me an issue.
Hold on one second. Lucky dot, lucky dot name.
OK, hold on. You're Reid. Gender, yes, thank you.
So that gender. And let's see if that fixes it, Robert.
Name name has given me. So let me just go right here.
So don't name names, I think name may be a reserved word.
Let's just call it. What's another word for name?
What's another variable for name that I could use, I don't. OK, very formal now.
OK, so I'm just going to change name to title. Let's see if it works now.
Go. Sized up, my fault means you didn't switch the name or the title.
One with code, let's just check my code self read.
So I have one two three four five one two three four five.
Right there there's that one two three four five.
Lucky that breed. It should be working, it's working on mine.
Yeah. Hold on a second. Let me just run this again.
Yeah, hold on. What love to see what's going on here?
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. Signs that oh, look, look, look, see.
Self thought title self, that title name probably wouldn't work.
That was my goof ready. So there it is. There is Lindsay's dog and there is it's breed, right?
So in software, we have a variable called Lucki.
That's an object. And that object knows a whole bunch of things about itself.
It knows its breed, its gender, its color, its size and its title.
Right. Just like that. And if I create, I'll create my dog.
Dr. If a dog is a he's black and white model, actually, he is a English springer spaniel who is barking in the hallway right now.
English Springer Spaniel. And then he is a male dog.
He is color, he's black and white and he is thighs medium.
And his name is Tucker.
Okay, so I created right from this bunch of code here to objects that happen to be dogs that have one, two, three, four or five properties.
We have no methods. These dogs can't do anything right now.
And by the way, if I print out Tucker as they breed right, I can then see that Tucker is an English springer spaniel.
So I don't know about you, but everything, you know, kind of what we've learned in this class, right,
this this like totally changes the game because unlike anything else, we are creating a template.
Kind of like the graphics library, where we're able to define an object, right, which has.
Instance variables. These are instance variables, by the way, let me just put this here.
Instance, variables, that means for this instance of lucky and or Tucker, here are these values and each one is different.
But we made Lindsey's dog and my dog right in the software through this same template.
Okay. Should we take a break, by the way?
Should we take a break? 11 plus 11 plus 12 plus 10 is 22, so I'll stop the recorder.
What's? I'll stop the recorder I wanted to do right.
So, OK, so data, it's totally a natural thing to find coding difficult.
OK. That's good to know, because some people will make it look like it's easy.
And I probably taught maybe two thousand students over nine years, maybe not,
I don't one hundred and four, ninety five percent of those students, this stuff is very difficult.
But Joshua just know that a lot of the students that I do keep in touch with.
I have done really well, and they had this is their first programing course, so it takes time.
Right? Think about just think about high school, right?
And how many years we're taught like English, write English as a language, right?
It has syntax. It has semantics, just like all this stuff.
Right. And here we are nine weeks later with a new language.
And, you know, give yourself some credit for what you know already.
You may still not be as good as you.
One day will be at it, but I was I was that same person as Joshua, so and I still have a ton to learn.
So here we go. So there are two dogs and it says recording yes.
Does it say recording somewhere? Yup. All right.
I need to take my glasses off because my eyes lately are just I don't.
I don't. It's new glasses. I don't know if it's out or I don't know.
So here we go. We got two dogs. Yay.
Yay, we got two dogs. And right now, our dogs are kind of boring, right?
All right. One more dog. Let me create one more dog. I'll create Bella.
She was a dog of ours. She's no longer here. She was an English springer spaniel.
She was female. Notice how the type.
You notice how this is changing. See this right here. How it's highlighting what I need to do next.
She was tricolor. I'll just leave that to three colors.
She was a medium dog and her name was Bella.
Bella Luna, beautiful moment. And if I print out, like, print out Bella's value of, I don't know, gender, it's going to print out female, right?
So if I run this code, we got Lindsay's dog, our dog, and we have Bella, who is a female.
Right? So I have these three objects in my code that have these five properties, but they can't do anything right now.
Our dogs are unable to do anything. OK.
And also what I'm going to teach you is that you see how I'm accessing these property names like this breed, breed, gender.
I'm going to show you a better way to do this because this is but there's just always a better, more professional way to do things.
But again, think about this.
This is the first time in this class where we've created a template and we've made stuff just like from the graphics library.
We've we've we've used that template to craft to create Locky, Tucker and Bella in software.
OK, so let's go back. We need our dogs to be able to bark, right?
So what we need to do is define, define a new method.
Right in our class that all dogs can do our template,
that when we make all dogs and we're going to define a new method, lowercase bark just like that.
And we need to tell that particular dog itself to bark.
That's why I put self in there. And then I'm going to say print.
Woof, woof. Just like that, because that's how it Dogwood border, right?
We print out the words. Woof, woof. Right. So I could tell any of my dogs now.
To Bach. So let's take lucky and say, hey, lucky.
Bach, just like that. It's a method. We do the parentheses.
We don't give it. The self here just needs to be here, but we don't put it here.
And now when I run this. We've seen the same information and then we see Lindsay's dog walking.
And we could do the same for Tucker. And we could do the same for Bella.
Right, all these dogs are made from the same template, they can all do the same thing.
Now wouldn't it be nice? Instead of just Wolf Wolf, we knew which dog was barking, right?
So could I just say, could I just do this? Could I say, I'm going to use that string here because I'm being lazy?
And could I say, Hey, self, what's your title? Is your name?
Just like that. And now when I run it, it says Lucky Wolf.
Wolf Tucker. Wolf Wolf. Bella Luna Wolf with.
So I'm telling each one of those objects, what's your name?
What's your title? And then I'm putting out the words with. Or I could just do this.
Right, Bella Part Tucker barked, Lucky [INAUDIBLE].
So watch us. Lucky Tucker Park, Bella Luna Park, OK, I guess I was getting ahead of myself, I use the quotation marks.
What do you mean, Joshua? Like I try to like in the parentheses versus lucky breed?
I actually got lucky title collar quotation is a comma and then another quotation that says lucky breeds,
so they print out like lucky is the Black Lab colleague or.
Well, let's talk about that, right? So here we created our our three dogs.
We gave them a breed, gender, color, size and title.
Right. And there they are.
They all have this. Those five properties and all of them can bark, right?
All of them can bark, right? So let's do this again now and let's create.
We did bark. Let's do run. Let's create another method. Called Run, and we're going to tell you the dog, too.
And I'm just going to this copy this. What's?
So I'm just adding additional methods for each of those objects.
And now I can instead of Barak, I can say, Hey, hey, Tucker.
Park. Just like that. I meant run.
Sorry. Hey, Tucker. Run. Just like that again, these are all method bark run.
They're different things, and you can see here we're getting Tucker to run.
We're getting Tucker to run if I want to get if I want to get lucky to run her lucky run.
All three dogs made from the same template, the same class, all have five instance variables, five properties.
Right now they have two methods. They can bark and they can run and we can do the same thing with each jump and potty.
So if I say if I create a new method called potty. Kind of put that self in there, and I put in that.
Is going to stay. Just like that now when I want a particular dog to go potty, I'll say, Hey, Bella, go potty.
Now. Gerri, what do you think of this stuff?
It's pretty cool. It's a lot.
It is a lot, and it's it's the sheer fact that again, we're not creating function functions like do a bunch of code and then they're done.
Maybe they print something out. Maybe they send something back, but they forget everything they know.
And when we create objects, these objects live on right from this stuff that we created them with.
Right? They know their breed. They know all these properties.
They know they can bark, they know they can run, they know they can go potty.
And just like we did with the dye, let's say I want to create a pack of dogs, right?
I no longer want to create variables for each of my dogs because that's kind of not a we wouldn't do
that in in a professional environment because we would have to create variables for each of the dogs.
But what if we want to model what we did with the bag of dice, right?
The bag of dice and create a pack of dogs? Right. So I'm going to copy all this code and not mess this up.
Copy all that code. Go in, create a new program and paste it in.
Save it. I'm going to call this demo Dash six that way.
And instead of creating right, I'm just going to clean all this up instead of creating these variables here.
Right? What I'm going to do right is I am going to not just do this, I'm going to get rid of it all.
I'm going to create a list pack of dogs. There they are.
Pack of dogs. It's an empty list. But my job now is to be able to create like 100.
Dogs, right? I'm going to make the same dog for now, just for my example.
And then we're going to have them all go potty at the same time. OK, so how do I do that right?
For I in range of 100 creating a pack, 100 dogs.
Saying, Hey, pack of dogs, a pen to yourself, a new dog, and the dog is going to be a.
We're going to do poodles, OK? A poodle. The gender is going to be will make them all male.
We'll make the color, they're all white.
Will make the size all small, and we'll just call them instead of a name, we'll just call them a poodle just for now.
OK, so there is my pack of dogs. I just created.
Let me run it just to make sure it doesn't throw up. All right, good.
So in software, I've created a bunch of 100 dogs.
They're living in this pack of dogs. They're all in there. So how do I get them all to go potty, right?
I don't get them all to go potty. Well, I can say for every lowercase dog or four, I doesn't matter.
For dog in pack of dogs, for every pack of dogs is a list we can iterate through lists.
One list element at a time, Jerry. And then we can say, Hey dog, go potty.
Just like that. So I'm going back, I created 100 dogs.
And now I'm telling all those dogs to go potty. So let's do it.
Now they are they're all going potty at the same time.
Just by right, rating 100 of them and sticking each dog in a list and you know what a better name instead of a poodle.
Let's just call the name of the dog a number.
So I'm going to take I, which is the iterator zero, one, two, three or four.
And I'm going to make it into a string and we're going to call our dog a number.
Your dog zero, your dog one. That's that's your title.
And now. Please hold a.
So now you can see each of the dogs, dogs zero is going potty, one five all the way up through.
Don, ninety nine zero to ninety nine is 100, so now I have a pack of dogs made in software.
They're all the same, right? We're just being generic now.
But how about them apples? How about them apples?
Then think about games. Think about games and how we may create a player class.
And some of you saw the video that I shared with you all about what we're going to do on Wednesday is create a player class to.
To to do what kind of work we're doing here, but with gameplay.
Right. All your games have when you like. I didn't know nothing about games, right?
But you know you, you have maybe a name, you have armor, you have weapons, you have,
you know how you have all these different things and that's what kind of what we're doing here.
We're creating the template, the class for each doc or for each player or for each dot.
Yeah, it lends that question.
So lately I've been playing in like Sonic Forces, like on my computer, and I just realized something then this like code like,
how do you think they make different classes for each character's skills?
Like, how do they do that? So we're going to be doing that on Wednesday.
So just like because like a Ali, sorry, Ali.
No, no, no, no. You're cool. My eyes were just bugging me when we think about a list, right?
Your player has a list of skills or a list of weapons or a list of things that it can do.
And when we when we talk on Wednesday and when we develop a game,
one of the things that a player is going to have is a list of weapons, a list of skills and things like that.
All right, so. OK. Yeah. Yeah, good question.
Thanks. Let's do it just right. The out of this like on this play, this kind of looks like a game mechanic from a game I've been playing recently.
Yeah. Well, the whole point of this is this to show you just that.
If you can only write simple code like we've written all quarter long before,
you're going to have the need to do stuff like this, I didn't create variables for each dog.
They're not there. They are an element in a list or a pack of dogs, and they're all sitting in this list, all next to each other.
They don't fight, but there they are there.
If I change this to, you know. 100000 dogs.
Not that I want to have 100000 dogs go potty and print that out all at one time, right?
But there I go. I commit 100000 dogs or if I want like 10 dogs, there they go.
Right, there they go. Right? There they go, there are the 10 dogs 039 all going potty now.
The one thing I wanted to tell you kind of going back to what we had before and then we'll probably cut cut this on.
For today, because this is complex stuff, is I told you that it's not cool to say like dog got gender right or dog scholar.
It's better to create methods and this is on a quiz.
These are called getters and setters, accessories and beauty towards right getters and setters, not dogs, not Irish setters.
But here, let me take this out, getters. Sweaters or accessories mutate towards that's that the computer science name,
where these getters and setters are going to be a way for us to get the dog's breed.
But right now, we don't have a really good way of doing that or changing the dog's name, right?
Or something about that dog. We could say Dog, don't breed and change the dog's breed.
But you don't ever really want to do that. What you want to do is create waves in your code, in your class to gracefully change things.
You don't want to access these property names directly. It's a really bad habit.
So let's go in here and say define a new getter called get on the score breed self.
Return self-taught breed. Now that's kind of weird, right?
We're saying we created a method called Get Breed that we can call and we're saying, Hey, dog, look at yourself.
What kind of dog are you? And then it's going to say it's going to send back.
To me, the brief, this is the way that you should get information about your objects.
So now I can say right, instead of going potty, I can say dog dot.
Get on the score, breathe just like that.
Not not this, not dog, don't.
Dogs don't do that, don't do that bad. But look at I created a nice, elegant, programmatic way to get me the breed of a dog.
And now when I run this code? I get an error, right?
So what a team here, it's saying, oh, so it gave me that dog breed, but I didn't do anything with it.
Could I could I do this? Could I say print out?
Whatever got returned to me, that was my fault before, could I print it out and could I say, Yeah, they're all tools?
That's the way that you would do things. And I could do the same thing, create another.
Get her, get her, get the color.
Hey, dog, look at yourself. Return to whoever asked you what color you are.
And. Print out, Hey, dog, get your color.
Get your. Color just like that.
Getters and setters, these are accessories, accessories, we're accessing information,
we're accessing information about an object, about a dog, and we're saying, Hey dog, which a breed?
Look at yourself. Send back to me what you are and when I run it.
You can see here. Right, poodle, white, this is the color, and this is the professional way of returning information.
We never want to do this. That's bad. OK, that's bad.
That's a bad thing to do. And you saw me do it probably in some of the videos about the dye or the player class or something,
because I've learned so I've learned since I've made that video that it's better to do things and more pro right?
Best practice to do things like I'm doing here now. These are all good.
These are getters. This gets me information about a dog.
But what if I want to change the dog's name? Let's say we adopt the dog and the dog.
His name changes. So we need a way to mutate, to change, right?
To set the dog's name. And again.
This is the way to do it. We define a new method and we call it set getters and setters get ers and setters, not dogs, that will call it title.
We'll say, hey, self, it's time that you change your name.
Whatever new name I gave you. But when I changed the dog's name, I need to give it the the new title I need to like say, Hey, your new title is this?
And then you need to set yourself to it. So let's take.
Let's take all of the dogs and change their titles and their titles to begin with where the number zero three ninety nine?
Right? So how can I now go in?
I'm just going to come of these out for now. How could I go in and say, Hey, dog, hey, hey dog, set your title right?
There it is. Set. Title. But I need to give you a new right, a new number because we adopted or we adopted, you know, a hundred dogs.
So I'm going to say, Hey dog, take your, Oh, this is interesting.
How do I get the dogs? How do I get the dog's current title right now?
How do I get? Do I have a method where I can get their title?
Or do I need to create one to get their title? I need to create another method get the title of the dog.
That's the name and send it back. There we go.
These are this is the proper way to do things. So I have one dog.
Class. I construct the dog. I can tell the dog to park.
I can tell the dog to run. I could tell the dog to go potty if I need to get the dog breed.
I have a getter or a word access or method to do that.
I have a way to get the dog's color away, to get the dog's title and a way to set the dog's title.
And now down here we're saying, Hey, take your current title, your name.
Let's just do this. So I need to say, Hey, dog, what's your current title?
And I'm just going to add to that the string.
Just just give me a second here. Adopted. Just that.
Just that right there, I'm going to say, Hey, dog,
set your title to get your current title and add to yourself the word adopted and then go to yourself and that's your new name.
And then right after I do that, I can say, Hey, dog. Get your title.
We have a method to get a dog's title. We do right here and I'm going to print it out.
And now we can see all of our dogs adopted. Hopefully.
Yeah. All right. See that. Get title not defined.
See, I make errors. So what I need to do here is say, Hey dog, get your title.
Hey, don't get your title. And now when I run this, they're all going to be adopted.
See that all 10 dogs got named, renamed from zero one two three four five.
They've all been had their names change to their old name zero plus the word adopted.
Now, I don't know about you, this is some hairy stuff.
This is, you know, we went from writing simple programs to creating object oriented code, and I'm just trying to leave it all there.
And don't worry, I'll give you all the code. And it's a little mind boggling and it's a little overwhelming.
And I'm not going to overwhelm you with another half hour of what we've done today.
We'll do more of it on Wednesday. So thoughts on classes, I need some feedback.
I mean, I would appreciate some feedback. I think this is very interesting.
OK. It is somebody else. Could I do?
Can I do one more 10 minute example on the cars for today?
Is that is that OK? Just to help you out a little bit more? That's fine with me.
I'm good with that. All right. Let's just do that. All right. Sorry for that.
I have to go get my flu shot. All right, here we go.
To demo is this Demo six picked up on a demo.
Seven that fine. All right. All right, here we go.
Ready. Here we go. We're going to create a class to represent cars and cars ready so class.
Car, there it is, class car, no parentheses. Now we need to create our constructor.
Dunder Anek Dunder Self will fill in the rest in a minute.
We define our main. And now let's get going.
So when we construct the car, what are some of the things that the properties that cars have?
Make. Model.
What else, what? What else other color you're?
Let's go with that. Just for now. There we go.
So now we need to take these parameters right, these properties and put them up here.
Make. Model. Color. Yeah.
So when we construct the new car, there we go. OK, so let's create a new car.
Let's just go back to the way we've been doing it. Here we go. Let's create and we have a car.
Give me a car. Just belt one out. What about us over 2010, can we?
All right. So let's Korea, is that your car? All right.
So let's create. Lynn Lindsay's car variable, there it is, Lindsay's car, and we're going to create a new car and we're going to say hi to.
Camry. What color is it, Lindsey Silver, Silver and what year 2010, right?
Yeah. All right. So I could create the year as a number right, just like that doesn't have to be a strength, right?
And. There's Lindsay's car, there's Lindsay's car, right?
So there it is, right? But I taught you in the last lesson that I need to create some accessories for getters to be able to properly,
professionally get info about each and every car that we create.
So could I define a new method, a new accessory or a new getter that says get?
Underscore make. And I'll say, hey.
Send back whatever your make is, and could I do the same for model color in the air?
Let me do this, by the way. This is just like one of the programing assignment problems.
Although. One more and I'll fix everything.
So we got we got we got make. We got model and model.
They turn the model. Give me back the model.
We got the color. We got the color.
We got the color, and then we got the year, we got the year.
So this is cool because now we have things built into our code that can look at any car we present itself and say, Hey, what's your model?
What's your color? What's your year? And we're not. We're not doing what I showed you earlier.
We're not doing this. We're not saying, Hey, Lindsay's car. Hey, Lindsay's car in the car?
We're not saying that anymore. OK, that's that's bad because we want.
We want to be able to not just say, hey, what property, what, what color are you?
We want programmatic ways to be told what the color is.
OK? Just it's it's a little bit more than I want to share with you.
But this this this works well. It can be really dangerous.
So what I do now, as I say, Hey, Lindsay's car get.
Was it color? Is that the one, the color? What did they have before I had color?
Yeah. So I said, call the method, get color and tell me what color Lindsay's car is.
And it's silver. Right? And now I can say, print out, Hey, Lindsay's car, get your year.
What year are you? Get year? And it should say.
2010. There it is. And now when I create another object, I'll just do another one.
OK. Gales are.
Car. Alexis, what is it?
Model three left the color black, yeah.
Twenty sixteen. Right. And now I could do the same thing.
Ford girls car, which is just another object, and I'll do it right here.
I'll say, hey, what is Gail's? Car color and what is.
Gail. Car year and.
Black 2016. So to wrap it up, we create a model, not not car model, but a way in software template.
Right. A class that describes when we create a new car, what properties it should have.
And then we create a list of methods right for that particular object car class.
That can like do things get the model, get the get the mate, get the model, get the color, get the year.
In fact, we can add a new one that says maybe got a paint job, maybe the car got painted that color.
Upset caller, this last thing, by the way, and then we'll say, hey, hey, self, say your color to that new color that we're going to tell you to.
So I need to go here now and say, Hey. That's a new color.
And now I'm going to change Gail color of her car right after here, I'm going to say, check this out.
I'm going to say Gail's car. That sent color.
And we're going to make it purple. All right.
And then we're going to print out Gail's car color after we change it, we'll just do it down here and you'll see that.
We're going to be changing our color. It was black, and now it's purple.
I see all the smoke coming from all over your heads right now because this stuff is.
But then this is like if you're taking JavaScript, if you're taking HP, we're going to be using this concept over and over and over again.
A web page is actually an object. If you think about it.
It's this collection of HTML elements.
Some of them will have classes. I ds will have content between tags and everything in JavaScript isn't object in on the web page,
and we'll be using stuff like this to go get information about a paragraph.
Text about an image, so bear some context for you all the time at the tone is eleven, fifty nine and 17 seconds to.
Parting thoughts, questions, concerns. And look, and looking at you all.
That was not a single question in chat today. That does means everybody is toast.
So I know I know for a fact that kids watch our show.
I think I'm the only one to ask the question today.
There's something now, Jack Jerry says crickets.
Yeah, you know, remote zone. Tough stuff, man. Totally different in a physical classroom, right?
We'd be eating pizza right now. So tough concept.
It took me a long time to understand getting back to what Joshua mentioned before,
and it's very normal for new programmers like yourselves right to do things the way we used to do.
But once you understand how to represent. Something with.
Instance variables. With methods, right, getters and setters accesses accessories and mutates.
It your life as a software person can become you can step up your game a lot.
So one more thing in the chat, Lindsey gives a smile. OK.
So on Wednesday, we'll do a little bit more and then we'll I've created a game, a simple game using players that have different weapons,
and those weapons have different weights like a sword versus a bow versus a hammer.
They have all different weights.
So how can we write a game with, I don't know, a thousand players randomly battling one another, pulling out their weapons, having a battle.
One of them was going to die, and then how do we eventually get down to one player left?
Sounds like a big while, Luke, to me, sounds like a list of player objects and sounds like some decision logic.
And it sounds like some fun. So. I'm going to turn off the recorder.
Oh, by the way, there is a you should see in canvas now and something in Module nine to be able to leave feedback for for me in this course.
It's something that they do to me every quarter and I must say do to me, but I'm on this.
I'm on this practice. This thing at school where it's called tenure track, where they teach you how to teach right.
And that feedback gets seen by it gets seen by me like way after the course is over,
just so you know, it'll have no reflection on your grade will be, Oh Jerry, give me bad feedback.
But it's a way to to give the college information about me. The course the good, bad and ugly.
And a lot of you have done this before and you've done it for other instructors.
So it's not it's not required, but I highly encourage you to do it so.
When I loaded into Kansas today. Well, this might be odd, but it said I had a we acquired a weevil here,
weevil to do on you and then my English teacher, it was required and then I couldn't get out of it.
Oh, really? Oh, God, my belly button that said do later.
It did give me that button like so quickly before class with me almost late.
Oh all right. Well, I'll let. I'll let the people that handle that, I'll let them know.
But again, it's not required, but it's very, very helpful and I get to go over them.
They're all anonymous, and I'm really thankful for any type of feedback which you already know.
So with that, I'm not going to give me any more. I'm going to shut up and have a good day and I'll see on Wednesday.
You'll also have a good day to you and.